Think of a caveman, and maybe you imagine someone tearing at the flesh of an animal they've just hunted.
想到穴居人，也许你会想象他正撕扯着他们刚猎杀的动物的肉。
But this picture may be false – analysis of prehistoric remains suggests that Stone Age people were skilled in processing and cooking different kinds of seeds, even experimenting with different flavours.
但这幅画面可能是错误的——对史前遗迹的分析表明，石器时代的人们擅长加工和烹饪不同种类的种子，甚至尝试不同的风味。
Seeds are still an important part of our diets, so maybe food choices haven't changed as much as we think.
种子仍然是我们饮食的重要组成部分，所以也许食物选择并不像我们想象的那样变化那么大。
In botanical terms, seeds are what new plants grow from.
在植物学的术语中，种子是新植物生长的基础。
Strictly speaking, edible seeds include nuts, pulses and grains, and are a significant source of protein and calories worldwide.
严格来说，可食用的种子包括坚果、豆类和谷物，是全球蛋白质和卡路里的重要来源。
Between them, rice and bread are staple foods in most of the world.
其中，大米和面包是世界上大部分地区的主食。
Many cuisines use beans, whether cooked in stews or curries, or mashed into pastes, like hummus from the Middle East.
许多菜肴都使用豆类，无论是炖菜或咖喱，还是捣碎成糊状物，比如中东的鹰嘴豆泥。
This definition of seeds also includes coffee beans and the cocoa beans used to make chocolate.
这个定义还包括咖啡豆和用于制作巧克力的可可豆。
Added to these are culinary seeds.
除此之外，还有烹饪用的种子。
These are what we more often think of as seeds – we often buy them unprocessed and use them in cooking, whether as a seasoning, as part of a salad or as a topping for bread.
这些更常被我们认为是种子——我们经常购买未加工的种子，在烹饪中使用，无论是作为调味品、沙拉的一部分，还是配合面包一起吃。
This includes chia seeds, sesame seeds and flaxseed.
这包括奇亚籽、芝麻和亚麻籽。
There are clear health benefits to including these seeds in our diet.
将这些种子纳入我们的饮食有明确的健康益处。
They are high in dietary fibre, which is good for digestion and helps fight illnesses such as diabetes and bowel cancer.
它们富含膳食纤维，有助于消化，并有助于对抗糖尿病和肠癌等疾病。
They are also a good source of unsaturated fat.
它们也是不饱和脂肪的良好来源。
Experts believe that using this to replace saturated fats, such as those from meat and dairy products, can lower cholesterol and help keep our heart healthy.
专家认为，用其替代饱和脂肪，例如来自肉类和乳制品的脂肪，可以降低胆固醇，有助于保持心脏健康。
The minerals contained in many culinary seeds, such as zinc, copper, and folate, can be beneficial for the immune system.
许多烹饪用种子中所含的矿物质，如锌、铜和叶酸，对免疫系统有益。
However, it's not all good news.
然而，也并非全是好消息。
Seeds can cause an allergic reaction, especially sesame seeds.
种子可能引起过敏反应，尤其是芝麻。
Sesame is one of the top ten causes of food allergies in the UK.
在英国，芝麻是食物过敏的十大原因之一。
Different types of seeds can share allergy-causing proteins, and other seeds that can cause allergies include sunflower seeds and poppy seeds.
不同类型的种子可能含有共同的致敏蛋白质，其他可能引起过敏的种子包括葵花籽和罂粟籽。